epsb.ca 2011-05-25

# District-wide Privacy Statement

:: District-wide Privacy Statement

Edmonton Public Schools maintains websites to help you find information about the district, its programs, and services. The Communications Department, which publishes and maintains the districts' websites, is committed to ensuring your privacy while you visit us online.

We do not automatically gather any personal information from you, such as your name, phone number, or e-mail address. This information is only obtained if you provide it voluntarily, through contacting us via e-mail, or through an online form ( _see Information Collected in E-mails and Web Forms_ ).

The Edmonton Public Schools' website connects you to some district departments and schools. This privacy statement covers the main Edmonton Public Schools site and all websites that link to the statement.

Any personal information you do provide is managed according to the Alberta _Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act_. This means that, at the point of collection, you will be informed that your personal information is being collected, the purpose for which it is being collected, and that you have a right of access to the collected information.

When you visit this site, our Web server automatically collects a limited amount of standard information essential to the operation and evaluation of the Edmonton Public Schools' website. This information includes:

  * the page from which you arrived,
  * the date and time of your page request,
  * the IP address your computer is using to receive information,
  * the type and version of your browser, and
  * the name and size of the file you request.

This information helps us maintain our site and provide you with the information you require efficiently. Collected information is used only for this purpose. It is collected in compliance with section 32 (c) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIP) Act. 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small piece of text information that is sent to your browser when you access a website. Your browser will return this cookie information to the domain where the cookie originated. While we do not regularly use "cookies" to track how our visitors use the site, when cookies are used, they may be used to help you fill in forms or track your use of the sites. The length of time that the cookie will reside on your machine will depend upon the specific set-up of the particular sites you visit.

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you can refer to the help information in your browser software for information on how to disable cookies. If you wish to delete cookies from your machine, consult your browser's help files for instructions on how to do so.

**Information collected in e-mails and web forms**  
If you choose to provide us with personal information - as in an e-mail to a district employee, or by filling out a form with your personal information and submitting it to us through a website - we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. 

We treat e-mails with the same respect we treat letters sent to Edmonton Public Schools. We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to respond to you. We only share the information you give us with another department if your inquiry relates to that department.

**Security**  
The district's computer system uses software to monitor unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or damage the service we provide. No attempt is made to identify users or their usage patterns except during law enforcement investigations.

**Links to other sites**  
Our website contains many links to other sites. Links that are outside the Edmonton Public Schools website will open in a new browser window. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. We encourage you to view the privacy policy and disclaimers of the new site you are going to.

**More information**  
For more information about the statement described above, please contact:

---|---  
On-line Communications Supervisor | FOIP Head  
Edmonton Public Schools | Edmonton Public Schools  
(780) 429-8461 | (780) 429-8020
